avis.com 2000-08-15

# Avis Rent A Car - Privacy Policy

** Avis Privacy Policy  **

Avis respects your privacy and has created this privacy statement to demonstrate that commitment. The following policy discloses how we gather and use information through our Web site, [www.avis.com](http://www.avis.com/).

All information obtained through the Avis Web site is confidential. Information is requested to make your visit to the Avis Web site more productive and to provide a better Avis car rental experience.

**IP Data:**  
When you enter the Avis Web site, we collect your IP address. The IP address identifies your Internet Service Provider, but does not identify you as an individual. This information allows us to administer our site and diagnose any server problems. Additionally, this information is aggregated to provide broad demographic information, such as the geographic location of visitors and how long they stay on our site.

**Cookies:**  
Cookies are small text files placed on your computer by the Avis Web server. Each cookie contains unique characteristics so that our Web server can later recognize your computer. The Avis Web site uses cookies to make reserving a car faster and easier. Data, such as car, offer, and destination preferences, obtained through cookies is maintained in a secure manner and is used only for internal purposes. Avis does not collect personal information without your knowledge and permission, nor do we sell or rent any site visitor data. You may avoid the use of cookies by electing to "turn off cookies" on your browser settings.

**Security:**  
Credit card information is not required to make a reservation on the Avis Web site. However, any service applications that require personal data such as credit card information are protected by Secure Socket Layer (SSL). SSL is a technology used to encrypt your information during transmission.

**Email Usage:**  
Avis requires your email address in order to make a car rental reservation on our Web site. Your email address is used only to send an email confirmation of your reservation. Your email address is also required on forms requesting information, so that we may respond to you via email. Email addresses are only collected for profile use with your expressed permission. Avis only sends email to consumers who have elected to receive promotions and special offers via email. If you no longer want to receive promotional email from Avis, please contact us via email at [optout@avis.com](mailto:optout@avis.com).

To be excluded from future post office mailings, please use the Customer Mail Preference form on our site: [www.avis.com/talk_to_us/customer_mail_pref.html](http://www.avis.com/talk_to_us/customer_mail_pref.html)

The Avis Web site contains links to other sites. Avis is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or the practices of the Avis Web site, please contact us via email at [privacy@avis.com](mailto:privacy@avis.com).

* * *

Return to previous page
